When people tell you one day
that you could be earning $100,000 a
month, you
straightaway think, "Oh, my God,
my life would become so much better." What
they
don't tell you is the many ways in
which your life gets worse.
I'm here today to tell you
and to show you why you don't want
that and what
you need to do instead.
I'm going to be introducing to you
something called the
lifestyle business,
and I learned this concept from Daniel
Priestley.
The lifestyle business. Now,
it's worth noting this will not buy you
the
911 GT3,
probably won't put you in first class,
and it won't get you a
mansion to live in.
And I'm here today to tell you that's
completely fine.
The truth is,
you need to build this first.
Imagine in jujitsu,
the worst thing in the world I could ever
do is give you a
black belt before you've earned it.
To understand this,
I'm going to use myself as an example,
not because I'm amazing
or great.
I've just made a lot of mistakes in my
time of running a business.
So my brand at the moment
is made up of personal trainer, author,
"Sunday Times"
number one bestseller three times.
Not top 10, number 1.
And I just want to point out,
the reason that I got
that accolade isn't because I'm
that good at writing books.
It's because I'm that good at sales
and marketing.
Mentor with my business coaching
mentorship, which this video is about.
I suppose I could take the credit of being
a creator because I earn probably
several thousand a month from videos,
from views. Podcaster.
Coming up to 16 million downloads.
Latest podcast,
"The Problem With," out now.
What else do I do? Speaker.
Sold-out venues with over three
and a half thousand
people in them. But this one
is going to be the most important,
and that doesn't
mean you need to be a personal trainer to
learn from this.
We're going to use this one because this
is the first one, the beginning of the
journey, and without this one here,
we wouldn't have access to any of these
ones
around.
If it wasn't for this lifestyle business,
nothing else would exist.
And we're going to get into exactly what a
lifestyle business is, but it won't make
sense unless I explain this.
So the personal training business we need
to expand,
because it's not that simple. Stage one
is what I call face-to-face.
I was in a gym called Absolutely Fitness.
It was 20 pounds a month, which
is 40 Australian dollars.
It was a budget gym in an industrial
warehouse park, and I charged personal
training sessions, give or take,
for about 30 pounds an hour.
Some people less, some people more.
And the face-to-face business
is crucial because it's where I learned
everything.
Now, would I say that
was a lifestyle business?
Yes and no,
only because I came from corporate,
and in corporate, I had a certain
amount of holiday
that I could take a year.
I had to ask for permission to go on
holiday.
I had to wear a suit to work,
had to be clean-shaven.
It's why you'll never see me clean-shaven
now.
So when I became a personal trainer,
literally the very beginning of being
self-employed, there
were a lot of benefits to my lifestyle.
I could wake up when I want,
and interestingly,
when it's your own thing, you don't
mind waking up at 4:45 or 5:00 a.m.
When it's for someone else, you hate it.
Got to wear shorts to work, which
was amazing,
and I got to choose the hours I
worked. So already,
after doing my level three PT,
even in my first few months of
being a coach,
I'd created a lifestyle business.
I could say to my friends, "Yeah,
you may earn more money than me,
but you don't
get to go to work in shorts,
and you can't just cancel all your clients
on a Friday
because you've got to come down from
taking too many pills the weekend before."
I
could. Now,
I would say probably the most
that I could earn on an
average from this would be, let's say,
30 sessions per week.
30 by 30, what's that? 900.
And that's great. It's amazing.
And this is back in 2016 and beforehand.
So the thing I want to stress here is,
even back in 2014, 2015, this isn't a
life-changing amount of money.
Most of my friends in the corporate world
were
earning way more than me, but my life
was better from lifestyle design,
therefore,
my lifestyle business
was better than other peoples'.
I'd play a lot of rugby sevens away at
weekends.
So I'd say to my clients on a Friday,
"Hey, I'm going overseas to play rugby.
Can we move Friday?" "Yeah,
sure." "Can we do it on Monday instead?"
"Not a
problem." Most of those paid 10 blocks,
so I was just pushing revenue further down
the line. Now, interestingly, I'll admit,
back in this stage, 2016,
I had an email marketing email list,
and there is a screenshot where I
messaged my friend Lucy Lord celebrating
the fact that I'd got 190 emails in a
day. I couldn't believe it. It
was amazing.
And I was sending a lot of offers out to
people, and no one was buying my stuff.
Then had a psychedelic trip
that made me decide to move to Australia.
I'm not making this up, I promise.
And I told one of my clients,
called Jackie
Smith,
I was thinking of moving to Australia.
She stopped middle of the workout
and said, "You need to go." She goes,
it's her
biggest regret in her life
that she never went to Australia,
they had the
opportunity to go, and they never went.
So the next session she came in, she went,
"Have you booked your ticket?" Seeing
her emotion to my decision to move to
Australia kind of made me realize I had to
go. So very simply, even at stage one,
I sent an email out to everyone
saying, "Hey,
I'm going to start doing online coaching.
It's going to be 50 pounds a week.
Who's interested?" And I got 10 people.
So I'd been trying to sell a PDF program,
this fat loss guide, online, and no one
wanted it, and it was 20 pounds.
When I put out an offer for 50 pounds a
week, I
got 10 clients. So
when I moved to stage two, which
is online, that's 30
sessions, I went to 50 pound per week.
And to begin with, I
was making 500 pounds.
Now, again,
this is where a lot of people can get
confused.
To many people, they go, "Oh,
you went from a face-to-face business to
making 900
pounds a week.
You're now making 500 pounds.
Your life's got worse." No,
because now I was in Bali
with my laptop. Then I
was in Australia with my laptop,
and also the amount of time
that I was spending in front of people
went from 30 hours a week to zero hours
per week,
which gave me a lot more time for content
creation, email marketing,
ideation. I would even say at stage two,
I was the most
dangerous as a business person because I
could read a lot of books.
[chuckles] I would read books,
come up with fantastic concepts.
I'd put them into email marketing emails,
and I make sales out of them.
So again,
when we're talking about lifestyle
businesses, we can often get caught
up. 100K a month. Hold on. I
was nowhere near that.
Great life playing sevens.
Sweden, Denmark, Dubai, Amsterdam. Unreal.
I leveled up my life,
halving the amount of money I made going
online.
And if it wasn't for
that step down in revenue,
I wouldn't have been able to build
the ultimate lifestyle business
that I'm going to get onto in a second.
So one thing we need to do
is unbrainwash ourselves from the fact
that revenue
doesn't always attribute to the quality of
our life.
And sometimes we can make steps in what
can seem like an unconventional
direction, and yet it can benefit us
if we look at the whole of the big picture
as,
how does this benefit my lifestyle?
James at 500 pounds a week,
living on a beach with only 10 clients.
That was easy.
I could service some of them in 15 minutes
a week.
This then grew to what I'm going to call
2B.
It went to 55 pounds an hour,
and it ended up getting 72
clients at peak. Now,
the interesting thing here is
when it got to 72 clients,
which is about 4,000 pounds a week,
55 times
72. Yeah, call it 4K a week. Although
that sounds amazing, my
lifestyle got so much worse. Now,
in today's money, that's closer to
6,000 pounds because of inflation.
And I'm not a finance expert,
but from what I learned from "Damien Talks
Money" podcast,
we created inflation to make sure people
spent their money, and
that's why your money devalues every year.
And I'm not here to teach you finance.
I'm just saying that
if you haven't put your price...
prices up in a year,
you've actually become cheaper because of
inflation.
So that's another reason you need to
increase your prices.
Make sure Declan's not listening.
So when I had a significant uptick in
revenue, my lifestyle got a lot worse.
I remember developing a twitch in my eye.
I went to the opticians, they said,
"There's nothing wrong with your eye.
You're drinking too much caffeine,
and you're stressed." So even though I was
making amazing money through trying to
grow my business, my lifestyle had got
worse. So you can actually see here,
the quality of my life sometimes was
correlated in the opposite direction to
the amount of money I was making, and this
is kind of an important point from today.
Here, I was desperate to find a solution,
so I was
also signing my contract to go into
Fitness First.
Darren, who is one of my best mates now,
he had a friend called James, he was
leaving the gym. I said, "Why
are you leaving the gym?" He goes, "Oh,
I want to
build websites." I said,
"I've got an idea." He's now my partner in
the James Smith
Academy. So in 2017, I contracted James,
then became my business partner.
We're now 50/50 in the James Smith
Academy.
He does payroll, accounting,
KPIs for coaches,
all the stuff I don't want to do.
He works with the developers,
builds the app,
gets it on the Google Play Store.
One thing I would say is, if you
are going to go into business with
someone, please
don't go into business with people
that do the same thing as you.
Because if you're both the content
creators on the front end that
are promoting the
product,
one of you will work harder than the
other, and sometimes that's just not
a fair reflection,
and it can cause issues to fall out.
The reason that it works so well for me
and James is that I can't do his job, and
he can't do mine.
I don't want to do his job,
and he doesn't want to do mine.
Actually, twice in the business,
I've said to him,
"Whatever shareholder agreement
you want,
I'll accept." So we went from 80/20 to
60/40 to
50/50. And the same with my manager.
He's 20%, but he could be taking anything.
At the end of the day, I wouldn't know.
Again, he does things I don't want to do.
I do things he can't do.
Now, for the JSA,
we then had to hire coaches.
We had to build an app.
We had to build an infrastructure.
We had to set it up as a very important
business.
Now, this, let's say, we'll go US dollars,
one to two million a year, which sounds
amazing, but again, coaches,
the App Store take 30% of purchase.
We got coaches to pay,
we got developers we need to pay full
time.
So although that looks amazing, him
and I take a sensible salary out of that.
But the amazing thing about the James
Smith Academy was because I win the
business
and then it's passed over to coaches,
again, my lifestyle became a lot better,
which gave me the time to write the books,
to build other things, to grow.
Now, the reason I'm telling you this is,
first of all, we do want to scale our
businesses,
and I'll show you exactly how in a second.
But the second thing is,
we want to be mindful it's not just a
battle for revenue.
It is a fight for revenue
and lifestyle at the same time.
And if you do not have the lifestyle
component of this,
you will struggle to grow.
You'll make really good money.
But it reminds me of my time in
recruitment.
Just before I started working in
recruitment, someone said to me, "Oh,
the money's
really good, but you'll hate it."
And I thought, "How can I hate it
if the money's
really good?" And I hated it.
The money was really good.
So one thing that this kind of all
encompasses into is a system that
I've kind of built
and made up over the last few weeks.
Because my mentorship
is now in its 2.0 version.
I did a year, and then after a year,
I sat back and thought about all I've
learnt.
Because I'm not a finished product.
I'm working with hundreds
and hundreds of businesses,
I'm learning at an incredibly
accelerated rate. And very shortly,
I will then go into the process of making
the third iteration and version, which
is going to be everything I've learnt over
two years and a YouTube component.
But this is what I call it.
I call it the four S's.
Social being at the top, squeeze, sell,
scale.
So if you look at my PT online journey as
a brand, started on social
media on the 1st of April, 2014. 2015,
started getting email addresses.
Like I say, 119 a day, was unreal.
Selling,
I was really selling the wrong thing
for a long time, and it was only
when I put out that offer for online
coaching and
people started buying it, that I
was able to scale with the James Smith
Academy.
There is no way you can get through this.
Now, sorry to put you on the spot.
There is a lad called George in my
mentorship who wants to go fully online
because
he's moved to Greece. However,
he has neglected his socials for the last
few
months, as he said openly to me.
He hasn't even put his email list live.
He's now in the process of trying to sell.
But going to this stage without doing the
things you need to do in the two stages
before means this is going to fall on its
face. If you can't sell, you can't scale.
If you haven't got data from people,
you can't sell.
And if you're not taking email addresses
from people on your social media, you
can't sell. Now, just quickly,
before I get into the next part of the
video, in the
description,
the first link you're going to see
is 30 Ways in 30 Days.
You click on that,
you give me your best email address,
and I'm giving you 30 ways
of information to benefit your business
over the next 30 days.
And just before you think, "Nah,
not bothered." Even if the information was
rubbish, if you look at the way
that I segment it and break it down
and send it to
you over the next 30 days,
it's not even that it's there to sell to
you.
It's there for you to copy.
Because whatever realm you're in,
you could be an
accountant, you could be a lawyer,
whatever it is, you could use
that exact same
system to break down your clients to
getting that bit closer to doing business
with
you. So the link's in the description.
You can pause the video and do that now,
but it's important that you come back
because the next bit we're going to get
into is going to change your life.
The question you're going to ask yourself
is, why should I start with a lifestyle
business? And the answer is very simple.
Your first five years, it's going to suck.
It's going to be shit. Even
if you think about it like this.
I thought about this the other day.
All the people that work for me at the
moment, we've got Declan, Ollie,
a couple of
others,
they're not actually staff to me so much.
They're little entrepreneurs.
They're going to leave me in the next few
years, and
I'm well aware of that.
And the only reason they're with me at the
moment is
because they want to learn from me.
I don't even think they want to work for
me.
They want to learn from me.
They're just working for me so they can
learn.
And that's completely fine because they
want to build their own lifestyle
businesses. Because at the moment,
the people that work for me, what day
are we
working this week?
What time am I going to be in?
You even asked if you could work remote
the other day.
I was like, "You always work remote.
You don't even have to ask permission,
mate.
Have a week off."
But the lifestyle business,
first five years is going to suck.
Because Declan doesn't particularly want
to be here right now.
He's just doing it for the money.
But in five years' time,
after having to take all
the abuse and the shouting
and me throwing chairs and tables at him,
he will be in
a position that he can no longer run a
lifestyle business
and build his own empire.
So if you think the first five years,
they're going to pay good, but they're not
going to pay that well.
The lifestyle's going to be good.
It's going to be quite stressful.
You're certainly not going to have a
business
that you can walk away from.
One terminology they have in business
is you either
have a puppy or a baby. Now, a baby,
you work really hard with the business for
years, it takes care of itself. A puppy,
no matter how many years you put into it,
you still need to take care of it every
day.
Your lifestyle business
is going to be a puppy.
Very rarely is it going to be something
that you can just walk away from,
and it'll
take care of itself. 2014,
started posting content.
2016, moved to Australia
Living out of hostels. 2017,
fell in love with an Australian,
went on her
visa, thought my future was set.
Two weeks later, we broke up and I lost
my visa and had to leave the country.
Moved to Bali.
And although this can seem romanticized
that I moved to Bali, Darren
and I actually
went at the same time.
Darren canceled his wedding three months
before.
His friends had all bought tickets to it.
He had started seeing what I
was doing online and realized
that there was so
much more he could do with his life,
and he realized that he
was made for more than
just being in the gym.
He had a lifestyle business,
but he wanted to take it to the
next level. Fast-forward a few years,
Darren is now the biggest online personal
trainer in Turkey with well over a million
followers.
But at this point,
even though people would have romanticized
our lives, we shared
a room in Bali. We got a twin room,
two twin beds. It was £20 a night.
Even though I was making really good
money, as far as the lifestyle business, I
wasn't splashing it.
We weren't renting expensive things.
We were just drinking bin tanks
and putting out content every day.
2018 into 2019, I had visa problems,
so moved to London.
Again,
I rented in a house with three other lads,
and my rent was £500 a
month. 2020, for the lockdown,
I actually had one day left on my visa
and flew
back to Australia from Bali.
Lived in a shared house with two other
lads
that was £150 a week, so £600 a month.
So even six years after my first video,
I'm living in shared
accommodation with two lads.
I'm actually in the loft,
and I've got a skylight.
If any of you lived in Bondi in 2020
and you see me running, I'm not out
exercising. It's about to rain
and my skylight is open.
2021,
have to come back to the UK for work
and events.
2022, get my visa. 2023, buy my first
house. 2024, launch this business,
Menship.
2025, actually 2024,
we launched New Tonic as well.
And now we're in 2026. And
if I'm completely honest with you, this
is fuck you
money. These years, okay, I
was earning more than I needed to spend,
but still wasn't really buying anything
from Gucci, wasn't paying off friends'
credit card debt or anything like that.
2021 to 2023, I was good.
First big pay slip went
and bought my parents a car.
Still rented,
but just rented nicer places,
and we're going to get into the tiers
of these in a second. So
if you look at my journey of operating
business, since
that first video I've posted,
it's taken quite a while to get here.
So the reason you need to have a lifestyle
business is if the money you're earning
is just going to be okay for the first few
years, and you guys can do it so much
quicker than I ever could.
I need your lives to be good here.
Because what's that saying?
The person that loves to walk,
walks further than
the person that loves the destination.
If I could tell you
that the next five years
are going to be a bit of a struggle, I
would say live within your means,
create a life of freedom,
work for yourself,
and build something slowly,
which means that your happiness and your
lifestyle comes at the forefront.
Because if I hadn't prioritized that,
we wouldn't have got to the good
or the fuck
you money. Now, what I've done
is I've actually broken down the growth of
your next
few years into three tiers, and
when you understand these tiers,
it's actually
going to clarify a lot of things for you,
and it could get you excited.
Some of you, probably the most of you,
are going to be in tier one.
Now, it can sound crazy,
but one of the first things you want to do
is just pay
your bills.
You're going to have bills for using
different services.
Maybe it's leadpages.com,
maybe it's Adobe Premiere Pro,
could be whatever it
is.
You also want to be able to pay your rent
and just cover your head, phone bill,
whatever it is. I'd say in tier one,
you want to consider travel laying down,
whether that's upgrading at the airport
or whether it's saving up to go on a
little
trip or a holiday. The reason
that I put this in tier one
and not in the further
tiers down is this
is where you can do something called
tasting your future.
So there aren't many things you can do
where you actually get to experience your
future.
And even if you rent a luxury car in
Dubai, I drove an event store around.
I absolutely hated it because I
was so worried I was going to ding it
or get a
scratch on it,
and I couldn't really enjoy the process.
But when it comes to business class
and you get a taste
and experience what the
future of your life could look like,
it's very motivating.
And I don't think people
are often the same once they've done that.
So even if you scrap together the very
first amount of money that
you have to travel laying down,
you can do it.
It's one of the reasons why on Declan's
first work trip, I upgraded him to
business,
so we get a taste of what his future will
look like if he doesn't get
sacked. Now, the next thing
that I would say to you
is to upgrade your setup.
One of the reasons
that you might be enjoying this video
is the fact we're using
two cameras and a high-quality microphone
in a studio.
I'm not saying you need that,
but just sorting out a microphone,
little DJI or a
little Hollyland something,
that's going to improve the level of your
content so
much.
Then getting a camera just gives you so
much more versatility.
Even getting a digital camera with Sony,
plug it into your laptop, go live on
YouTube, boom.
You just unlocked webinars
and live streams.
So tier one is through paying your bills
and through improving your
setup,
you can then actually make more money,
and through traveling laying down,
you can actually upgrade your mindset to
the point that you're like, "Wow, I want
to do this again." Once you've been
business class in tier one, kind of a
crazy thing is you never sleep through an
alarm ever again.
Unlike what I did this morning
and missed a flight.
But don't worry about that.
We're not bothered by it now. It
was only eight grand to change.
You're probably thinking, "God, this
is actually a really good quality video,
James." Yes,
because I need to make back the money I
lost today from missing a
flight. But anyway, tier one, this
is not to get distracted.
Just because you've earned above your
means doesn't mean you go buy a Lambo
or you
upgrade your housing setup. These
are the three things
that you want to prioritize
in tier one. Now,
quickly before I get into tier two,
some of you might have seen
my videos online where I critique people's
content, and I go through and I look at
their Instagram bio and the website
and point out differences in it.
I'm about to go traveling.
They're the only videos
that I'm going to be making, so
I need you guys to click the second link
in the description, which is going to be
that. If you click on that,
you just give me your socials
and email address.
I'll include you in the next video.
There are people out there who've said,
"James, never joined your program, but the
things that you told me to change on the
website, I'm already seeing an increase in
sales." So do that
if you haven't already Then we'll get into
tier two.
You learning, Declan? Okay,
once you've done tier one
and completed it, mate, we're
going to go into tier two.
And this could take a few years,
but it doesn't really
matter. Independent housing.
What I mean by this is whether you rent,
get your own
place. Because being a content creator,
the reason that I now only film in a
studio
is I need to actually be
semi-performative, and if my missus
is cooking a meal in
the background, I can't be that person.
When you have your own space,
you can be creative,
you can film in the evenings.
Whenever those creative juices come to
you, you can do what you want.
When you have housemates
and they're back from work,
and you've got to keep the
noise down,
and you want to do a podcast with someone
that's overseas, and they
want to talk at 1:00 in the morning.
I think I've literally just spelled
independent wrong. Is it independent?
Independent. It doesn't matter.
I didn't make it here for my ability to
spell.
So if you can scrape enough money to get
your own place with a spare room that
could be your office,
can be a place to film content, whatever,
that is another big
key place of being able to have a return
on investment.
Even if you could just have a room in a
house, it might not be the ideal place you
want to live, but trust me,
having a room where you can leave the
camera set up,
leave the lights in place, so you come in,
turn it on, press record, it's going
to allow you to make more content in less
time with less friction and barriers to
entry, which again means more content.
Remember the four S's, social, squeeze,
sell, scale.
It's going to be more people attributing
down there, and it's going to make your
life so much easier.
We can also start to appreciate to look
into potentially a
second business. So as a PT,
you might bring a coach in underneath you,
or you might hire a nutritionist.
As a lawyer,
it might be another member of staff.
Or it could be something completely
different.
As a PT,
you might start a supplement line,
or you might make some eye masks, or
you might start selling saunas as a side
hustle, whatever it is.
Because at tier two,
you've learned a lot to get out of tier
one.
You've had to learn how to operate social
media, how to build an email list.
We're going to get into that in a second.
You can start to flirt with the idea of a
second business.
Now, because all your bills are paid
and everything's covered, this is a great
venture because the pressure on you to
make sales to cover your life isn't really
there anymore.
This could be offering out consultancy to
other areas.
You could even just sell your time.
Even someone as PT,
you might even just start putting an hour
in your calendar for
£200 and say, "Hey,
if you want a program and a consult,
and to go through your
diet," whatever it is. Even
if people don't buy it, you're fine.
But you can start setting up a second
business and start making changes with
your
brand. For me, the second business
was books, and then from the books, we did
events. And I shit you not, there
are some events where we'd sold more
tickets to
the event than we had books that week.
I put in studio and space for some of you.
If you can't get independent housing,
it sometimes can be cheaper to rent a
studio and remain living where you're
living.
So the issue is,
if you make a bigger house
and it costs you $1,000
more a month,
it doesn't just cost you $1,000 more a
month because you've got to
pay tax on the money. And
if you're in the relatively high tax
bracket, that means
you're earning 1,600 to pay tax to have
1,000.
Whereas if you get a studio space that
is wholly and exclusively for the
business,
this isn't financial advice,
if that's $1,000,
you're going to pay $1,000.
So there's going to be a tax incentive for
you to potentially, in some cases,
not get a spare room
and get a studio instead.
Probably the most important of tier two
is you're going to start looking at your
first hire. Now, people say,
"You should see how happy you would be
if you got a
Ferrari." Do you know also how happy you
would be if you got a fucking assistant?
Whether virtual, Philippines, in-person,
whatever.
But my first hire,
seeing as I'm very content-heavy as a
creator, was a
videographer. Now, it
was very difficult for me.
It took me years before I finally hired a
videographer. Very important move.
I know that some of you,
if you're autistic like me,
you might think they can't do
as well a job as you,
or you can train them,
they'll learn quick on the job.
Find someone good, pay them well.
Then the amazing thing is,
even after today, once
I finish this video,
Declan can just take the memory card,
go off, be happy, live
his life, and I'll get an edit out of it.
Very important that you start delegating
at a point that you can because your
time, rather than in the edit,
could be spent making another video.
So if you're doing an hour of recording,
an hour of editing, which is never going
to be like that, an hour of recording,
three hours of editing, those three hours
could make another three videos.
And again, the return on investment.
If you get a spare room,
return on investment.
Second business, return on investment,
and diversification and everything else.
Return on investment, studio,
return on investment, first hire.
So everything,
we're not even at the fuck you money.
Everything almost so far,
apart from the business class flight,
has a return on
investment because it's about doubling
down. It's about reinvesting.
When you guys invest into stocks
and shares, when you get your dividends,
you put
it back in because
that allows you to get the effects of
compounding.
Tier two, very important.
Could take a few years,
might even take you a few months.
But all the people that you follow online,
all the gurus telling you to earn 100K a
month,
you're not going to earn 100K a month at
tier two, and we're years away from
that.
So why are they making videos for novices
saying, "How you make your first
100K a month?" Shut up. Tier three,
the meta.
Tier three is where you've kind of got
into outer orbit, and the crazy
thing is there's that saying,
a spaceship will use the majority of its
fuel getting
up into space. I think 80% of the fuel,
first 20% of the journey, something like
that. It's the same.
Once you're at tier three,
you're cruising.
Now, once you're here, and some of you
are here and you don't even know you're
here, you're going to want a nice house.
Whether you rent it or you buy it,
get a nice house because at tier three,
you are
now being judged with every single move
you make.
Even if your business is B2C or B2B,
people see you in a nice house, they go,
"His
business must be good,"
or "Her business must be amazing."
And by doing so, there's
that associative part of that
which makes them want to do business with
you.
If you're at tier three
and you've got staff
and you're crushing and whatever, and
you're living in a shady shack,
it's going to have a detriment to your
business.
I wish it wasn't this way,
it's just the way it is.
But also,
you kind of deserve a nice house.
Even if your burn rate on rent
is enough to make your parents go,
"I can't believe
you're spending that much on rent," it's
kind of a part of the brand incentive.
If you look at Daniel Priestley's videos,
if you look at anyone in that business
guru space,
they'll often show you a backdrop
that shows the grandiosity of their
financial freedom. Everything is a signal.
Whenever you see a creator make a video in
his car, you'll always notice their head
is a little bit off the mark as
if they're slipping a fucking cross
or a jab
so they can show you the stitching of the
car they're in. Lamborghini, Porsche.
I've been guilty of it. Guilty.
So you're going to want to get the nice
house.
Sports car's going to be another one
that you're probably going to want to get
at
tier three. Again, it sounds stupid.
Adam Sullivan, good friend of mine,
bought a Lamborghini Urus.
Financially,
one of the worst decisions he ever made.
Got the whole of the Gold Coast talking
about it. "How's this PT got an Urus?
How's this PT got an Urus?" Had the
biggest month of his professional career
up
until that point. Again,
it's this associativeness
that goes into your brand.
Unfortunately Especially in the fitness
space or whatever it is.
Without these two things,
people will just judge you.
They'll go, "Oh,
if he's not got a nice house
or a nice car." And again, I've been
guilty of this. Bought my dream home.
Don't put it too much on socials because
people are weird.
But since getting a nice car,
I've had more people coming to me for
business
advice, which is crazy.
People in my network, people
that I've known for years.
"Oh, Smith,
do you reckon I could just ask you a
couple of questions about this?"
I'm like, "You never asked me that
when I was driving an Audi
or a fucking Golf."
So it's a weird one,
but it also gives you excuse to do it.
So for me,
that expense should be considered,
because if you're really, really good
at what you do,
you should have a good life.
Because even if you're just someone's
personal trainer, or you're their lawyer,
or
you're their accountant,
they semi want to aspire.
They want people
that share the same values as them.
And if you drive a car that they want,
it's an associative way that they're going
to connect with you and bond with you.
You then have to move into a team.
Team of people, staff,
staff managing staff,
people overlooking staff, group
calls, finding what your staff are doing,
find out what your staff aren't doing.
Product. Most of you at tier one
and two are going to be selling a service.
It's only when you get to tier three you
can sell a product.
Again, if we use Adam Sullivan, EBT,
as an example,
he made his way through tier
one and two selling his evidence-based
training coaching, same as me.
I used James Smith Academy and the books.
Tier three was when I first brought out a
product, being Nushonic.
But if you jump to tier three to try
and sell a product,
you're going to struggle a
little bit because you haven't done the
work before.
Adam's product would be his gummies,
the creatine gummies, cunnies gummies,
whatever you want to call them.
So the product often occurs at tier three.
People don't just really realize it.
Probably start looking at first class in
tier three. Again, optics.
If you're in tier two, tier one,
don't do first class.
I did it a bit to flex, but
that upgrade could've bought me a new
camera.
What was crazy was, imagine this.
First time I flew first class,
I had a really bad
come down. First of all,
I booked one way to get home, which
was ridiculous,
because it's only about 10,
20% more to get return.
So wasted about four grand doing that.
Also,
when I got home from flying first class,
I went to my apartment.
My first class flight was $10,000.
My bed was $175 that I got from Facebook
Marketplace.
So I was like, "James, what
were you thinking?
If you'd just flown business, you prick,
you would've had another spare few
thousand dollars.
You could've bought yourself a new bed
that you're going to sleep
in every single night." So yeah, idiot.
And then lastly,
would be the consideration to move into
business to business.
So that's what I did
when I hit tier three.
And what this means
is everything in tier one
and two didn't help people make more
money.
The books help them with maybe something
to listen to, entertainment,
solving a problem.
The coaching apps provide programs,
accountability, et cetera.
The talks, entertainment. It's only
when I got to tier three that I
was able to
teach people how to make more money,
which is what I'm doing right now.
And the beauty about this is sales
are a lot easier
when you teach people how to
make more money. Because, for instance,
any of you click the third link in the bio
to work with me. You pay me $3,500.
I hope that within a year you've made ten
times
that back. Because everything
that I'm teaching you here and before,
if you get
that right,
you get to unlock tapping into so much
more business.
But this isn't a video about getting you
to join my mentorship.
Not directly anyway. At this point,
you go, "Oh my God,
this guy makes more sense
than any of the other gurus." Yes,
because I didn't get lucky once.
Got lucky about six times so far.
Even my product in tier three,
it's doing a
million dollars a month.
It's about to do a whole lot more.
Where was I?
Business to business. So any of you,
even you golf instructors watching or
whatever, or personal trainers,
it's crazy.
If you spearhead success with all the
things that I teach you,
eventually in five
years' time, maybe 10 years' time,
you'll be able to sell
that on to other people.
So for instance, Declan here,
probably within three or four years,
will have a
program for editors,
which may include cold outreaching to
people to work with
him for free, which he did with my barber.
So let's get to the crux of this video.
Whichever tier you're in,
it doesn't matter right now, to be honest.
I'm just showing you what you need to
prioritize and where you're at.
Because some of you might be at tier two,
and you go, "Oh, I really need to be
validated with that."
But the one thing you've not been told
is when you get to
this tier three, there
is so much more stress.
This is where you hit the $100,000 a
month.
I know because I'm here right now,
and it really annoys me
that people romanticize
this. When I wasn't happier at tier one.
My God, life was easy, it was fun.
I could nap more.
There was nothing to worry about.
Tier two, I was living my best life,
napping
twice in a day. When you hit tier three,
you see the sports car, and you see the
nice house, and you see first class,
but there's so much more here
that can stress
you out. Nice house.
Let's say business has a downturn.
You worry about losing it.
You got the nice car. You go on holiday,
and you think, "Wow, that car has just
appreciated five grand since I went home
to see my family." The team, you've got
good highs, but you also got bad highs.
You got people that lie to you, deceptive.
People you fly over from the UK,
and then they don't do any work,
and you've got to
send them back.
You bring out a product where you might
have $3 million worth of
stock just floating around at any given
point.
You sit in first class, and you think,
"Wow, I should have just saved the money
here." You launch B2B,
and you're not sure what content to make.
So for instance, some days I wake up
and I'm like,
"What business do I make content
for?
Where am I going to give my attention?
Oh,
I've got a fitness challenge going here.
I've got my business to business stuff
here. I've got to get in the Discord.
I've got to do that." Currently,
where I'm at, I am in that period where
the money is really, really good,
but my life is very, very busy,
and I'm stressed.
And tier four for me,
I don't even like talking about it because
I don't want to
jinx it.
Let's say Coca-Cola come along and in two,
three years' time, they
buy Nushonic for 500 million.
Then I'll reach tier four.
But I don't even want to jinx it, right?
Because then I'll be here making videos,
and the title will be "How I Sold My
Business for 400 Million
and I'm Still Depressed." There's always
going to be
another tier to move up to,
and just the amount of money
that you make per month or
per week isn't enough to determine whether
or not you're doing well or not doing
well. As you climb the tiers,
life gets better, but it also gets worse.
And for some of you that are at tier one,
you might be crying about it, thinking,
"Oh, I'm not achieving enough," or,
"I'm still only a PT in a gym," or, "My
accountancy firm's only three people."
But I'm here to say enjoy that period.
Because the higher you go, first of all,
the more expensive the cars to get a
thrill, the more expensive the flights,
the more expensive the hotels.
There are a lot of negatives
that come to it.
And I look back at the version of myself
five, six years ago, fuck, ten years ago.
I loved flying economy. I
was just grateful to see the world.
Now, if I had to fly economy, I'd be like,
"Oh, this is really going to suck." I
even look back three years ago.
I loved my Golf R. I was happy as.
Now I look at it and I'm like,
"It's the spare car." It's not
that I've become an
arsehole. It's the hedonic treadmill
that you climb that you need to in a bid
to grow every other part of your business.
You don't talk to a member of staff for a
week. You've still got to pay them.
So don't wish your life away for the 100K
months. Enjoy the stage you're at now.
Because before you know it,
it's going to be over,
and you're going to be at tier
two,
then you're going to be at tier three.
Every stage you should enjoy.
I'll have my black belt probably in a
year's time, and I'll look back at every
single belt, white, blue, purple, brown,
black, and I'm going to love all of them
the exact same amount, even though I
was very different in competence the whole
way
through. The biggest issue here is
when you're at your tier grade and you're
comparing it to someone else's.
If you're at tier one
and you compare someone at
tier three,
you're never going to feel good about
yourself.
If you are watching this,
you do not need to make $100,000 a month
to be very
happy, to live an amazing life,
to travel the world,
to treat your family and
friends amazingly.
You need to appreciate what tier you're
at, prioritize the right
things within that tier,
and then set your eyes on the tier above.
Maybe it's two, maybe it's three.
I don't know where you're at.
I am not a business genius.
I am just a couple of tiers ahead of you,
and that
is the product and the service
that I sell.
I sometimes think
that some of the techniques
that I've learnt in jujitsu from a
purple belt are better than the ones
that I learnt from a black belt because
the
purple belt was me two years ago.
But the black belt hasn't been the level
I'm at
for ten years.
I think that's what makes me a better
mentor.
Eight years ago, I was still in the gym.
Four years ago, I
was still in the shared house with my
mates.
Two years ago,
I was still driving a Golf R.
Now,
from everything we've spoken about today,
there is an exception to the rule
for personal trainers.
Because the rules are different,
and the game you can play
in 2026 means that you guys can actually
hit 100K a month without having even to go
to tier two or tier three.
But the only way
that you're going to be able to get it
is if you watch this video right here.
Thanks for watching. See what I did there?
Going to fucking put the little video in
it, bruv. Come on.